<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on The Realm of Space</title>
    <link>https://zkanda.github.io/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on The Realm of Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 21:55:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zkanda.github.io/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our experience in resizing an EBS volume in EC2 instances.</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/resize-ebs-volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 21:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/resize-ebs-volume/</guid>
      <description>Increasing disk space without downtime.
So in our team, we had to resize an instance disk because it&amp;rsquo;s getting full, this is our experience.
For the first time we search on how to do this, there&amp;rsquo;s many article written about it and most of them requires to stop the system and detaching a volume. But there must be a real docs from aws itself, that is most likely up to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling UDP in memcached.</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/disabling-udp-in-memcached/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 17:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/disabling-udp-in-memcached/</guid>
      <description>One of our server provider which is running in Germany have a bot that scan for open port, this is to prevent other human/robot in abusing services that are open in the internet.
For us, they determined that our memcached port is open, we were confused at first how could this happen, we were sure that this is blocked via iptables.
It turns out memcached by default listens to both TCP and UDP, since we don&amp;rsquo;t have yet a firewall for UDP, we opted for something simpler and to disable UDP on memcached(we know we only use TCP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating a configmap/secrets in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/updating-a-configmap-secrets-in-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 01:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/updating-a-configmap-secrets-in-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>At work, we started using Kubernetes for stateless application. We frequently change the values of configmap/secrets especially in staging environments, however, this is still not baked in to k8s.
How to do it?
You have to replaced a config to update it.
For example, if you create a configmap like this:
kubectl create configmap site-config --from-file=nginx.conf  If you want to update that, you have to add the command above with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>golang: defer inside a for loop</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/defer-inside-a-for-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 09:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/defer-inside-a-for-loop/</guid>
      <description>So I have an infinite for loop however I want to use defer to make my intention clearer.
Problem is this defer would never run because my function wouldn&amp;rsquo;t return. This in turn would give you memory leak.
As neat as it could be, you can use a closure/anonymous function for this.
for x := 0; x &amp;lt; 2; x++ { func() { defer fmt.Println(x) }() }  Real world use case: So what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to do is to have an infinite polling using context on AWS SQS to add a timeout if something is wrong with SQS(this can be anything from network errors to aws being down, it can happen).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Elasticsearch on a 2GB Digital Ocean Droplet</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/running-elasticsearch-on-a-2gb-digital-ocean-droplet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 04:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/running-elasticsearch-on-a-2gb-digital-ocean-droplet/</guid>
      <description>So I want to run Elasticsearch on a very limited memory machine and I keep running on this error: cannot allocate memory.
Did some research and found this docs on increasing max_map_count:
echo &amp;quot;vm.max_map_count=262144&amp;quot; | sudo tee -a /etc/sysctl.conf sudo sysctl -w vm.max_map_count=262144  But the problem still persist, turns out memory still actually still not enough. I want don&amp;rsquo;t to upgrade the memory since I just want to test things out and I have no plan on running it on production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GopherConSG 2017 Reflection</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/gophercon-sg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 02:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/gophercon-sg/</guid>
      <description>This is first time attending a conference outside my country. It was pretty exciting and scary because I&amp;rsquo;m going alone but nonetheless it was an amazing experience.
I met a couple of interesting people and mostly I think it boost more my confidence in travelling.
The first day was all about learning Go for Intermediate developers by William Kennedy.
I learned quite a lot, although I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Go in work for some time now, I admit that I still have a long way to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing python packages directly from Github using pip.</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/installing-python-packages-directly-from-github-using-pip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 03:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/installing-python-packages-directly-from-github-using-pip/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I needed to install a package directly from Github which I&amp;rsquo;m trying to contribute into.
For example you have this url: https://github.com/zkanda/lambda-uploader
What you can do is just add git+ as prefix in the URL.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how you can do it!
pip install git+https://github.com/zkanda/lambda-uploader  But the code that I want to install is from another branch, so how do we do it? We just add @branch_name at the end of the url.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting vi mode on IPython 5</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/setting-vi-mode-on-ipython-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 20:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/setting-vi-mode-on-ipython-5/</guid>
      <description>I just upgraded my IPython version to 5 and one thing that I&amp;rsquo;m missing is my vi mode binding. When I read the changelog, they now replace readline with prompt_toolkit a pure python interactive command line prompt. This is very nice because it supports all platform that python supports.
So to bring back your vi binding, you need to do this.
ipython profile create  This will create a default profile where you can change your IPython configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling the latest beta kernel in ArchLinux</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/compiling-the-latest-beta-kernel-in-archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/compiling-the-latest-beta-kernel-in-archlinux/</guid>
      <description>You have a new laptop, you install ArchLinux on it and seems like a some things is missing. Certainly this is the case for me, one of this is suspend feature, when doing, my laptop just seems to boot as if I shutdown it, my application is not persisted. Another is a fix for my headphone noise issue, just to name a few.
 Some things is missing!
 One of the few things you can try is to install the latest beta kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>