<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on intimacy of my thoughts</title><link>https://zkanda.io/categories/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on intimacy of my thoughts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 22:55:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zkanda.io/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>our experience in resizing an ebs volume in ec2 instances.</title><link>https://zkanda.io/dev/experience-in-resizing-an-ebs-volume-in-ec2-instances/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 22:55:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zkanda.io/dev/experience-in-resizing-an-ebs-volume-in-ec2-instances/</guid><description>Increasing disk space without downtime.
So in our team, we had to resize an instance disk because it&amp;rsquo;s getting full, this is our experience.
For the first time we search on how to do this, there are many articles written about it and most of them require to stop the system and detaching a volume. But there must be a real doc from aws itself, that is most likely up to date.</description></item><item><title>running elasticsearch on a 2gb digital ocean droplet</title><link>https://zkanda.io/dev/running-elasticsearch-on-a-2gb-digital-ocean-droplet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 05:46:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zkanda.io/dev/running-elasticsearch-on-a-2gb-digital-ocean-droplet/</guid><description>So I want to run Elasticsearch on a very limited memory machine and I keep running on this error: cannot allocate memory.
Did some research and found this docs on increasing max_map_count:
echo &amp;#34;vm.max_map_count=262144&amp;#34; | sudo tee -a /etc/sysctl.conf sudo sysctl -w vm.max_map_count=262144 But the problem still persists, turns out memory still actually still not enough. I want don&amp;rsquo;t to upgrade the memory since I just want to test things out and I have no plan on running it on production.</description></item><item><title>compiling a beta kernel in archlinux</title><link>https://zkanda.io/dev/compiling-the-latest-beta-kernel-in-archlinux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 01:19:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zkanda.io/dev/compiling-the-latest-beta-kernel-in-archlinux/</guid><description>You have a new laptop, you install ArchLinux on it and seems like some things are missing. This is currently the case for me:
one missing feature was &amp;ldquo;suspend&amp;rdquo;, my laptop just seems to boot as if I turned off everything, my application is not persisted another is a fix for my headphone noise issue, just to name a few&amp;hellip; One of the few things you can try is to install the latest beta kernel.</description></item></channel></rss>