<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on The Realm of Space</title>
    <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on The Realm of Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 06:42:21 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zkanda.github.io/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our experience in resizing an EBS volume in EC2 instances.</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/resize-ebs-volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 21:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/resize-ebs-volume/</guid>
      <description>Increasing disk space without downtime.
So in our team, we had to resize an instance disk because it&amp;rsquo;s getting full, this is our experience.
For the first time we search on how to do this, there&amp;rsquo;s many article written about it and most of them requires to stop the system and detaching a volume. But there must be a real docs from aws itself, that is most likely up to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling UDP in memcached.</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/disabling-udp-in-memcached/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 17:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/disabling-udp-in-memcached/</guid>
      <description>One of our server provider which is running in Germany have a bot that scan for open port, this is to prevent other human/robot in abusing services that are open in the internet.
For us, they determined that our memcached port is open, we were confused at first how could this happen, we were sure that this is blocked via iptables.
It turns out memcached by default listens to both TCP and UDP, since we don&amp;rsquo;t have yet a firewall for UDP, we opted for something simpler and to disable UDP on memcached(we know we only use TCP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating a configmap/secrets in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/updating-a-configmap-secrets-in-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 01:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/updating-a-configmap-secrets-in-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>At work, we started using Kubernetes for stateless application. We frequently change the values of configmap/secrets especially in staging environments, however, this is still not baked in to k8s.
How to do it?
You have to replaced a config to update it.
For example, if you create a configmap like this:
kubectl create configmap site-config --from-file=nginx.conf  If you want to update that, you have to add the command above with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give more..</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/give-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 22:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/give-more/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading a book called Give and Take, it made me realize the value of sharing on my blog and in everyday life, I hope to write more about things that I can give value to others as well as a constant reminder of things that have given me lots of &amp;ldquo;Aha&amp;rdquo; moments in my career as a Software Developer.
I really like the quote inside a quote in the book:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advance Testing in Go</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/advance-testing-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 15:06:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/advance-testing-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Test Methodology  Subtest  Closures Can target subtests Can nest subtests further  Table Driven Test  Low overhead to add new test cases Make testing exhaustive scenarios simple Makes reproducing reported issues simple Do this pattern a lot Followw pattern even for single cases, if it&amp;rsquo;s possible to grow Consider naming cases  Text fixtures.  go test sets pwd as package directory Use relative path &amp;ldquo;test-fixtures&amp;rdquo; directory as a place to store test data Very useful for loading config, model data, binary data, etc  Golden Files(Test Flags)  Compare complex test out to a file that has the expected result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>golang: defer inside a for loop</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/defer-inside-a-for-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 09:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/defer-inside-a-for-loop/</guid>
      <description>So I have an infinite for loop however I want to use defer to make my intention clearer.
Problem is this defer would never run because my function wouldn&amp;rsquo;t return. This in turn would give you memory leak.
As neat as it could be, you can use a closure/anonymous function for this.
for x := 0; x &amp;lt; 2; x++ { func() { defer fmt.Println(x) }() }  Real world use case: So what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to do is to have an infinite polling using context on AWS SQS to add a timeout if something is wrong with SQS(this can be anything from network errors to aws being down, it can happen).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Elasticsearch on a 2GB Digital Ocean Droplet</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/running-elasticsearch-on-a-2gb-digital-ocean-droplet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 04:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/running-elasticsearch-on-a-2gb-digital-ocean-droplet/</guid>
      <description>So I want to run Elasticsearch on a very limited memory machine and I keep running on this error: cannot allocate memory.
Did some research and found this docs on increasing max_map_count:
echo &amp;quot;vm.max_map_count=262144&amp;quot; | sudo tee -a /etc/sysctl.conf sudo sysctl -w vm.max_map_count=262144  But the problem still persist, turns out memory still actually still not enough. I want don&amp;rsquo;t to upgrade the memory since I just want to test things out and I have no plan on running it on production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GopherConSG 2017 Reflection</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/gophercon-sg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 02:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/gophercon-sg/</guid>
      <description>This is first time attending a conference outside my country. It was pretty exciting and scary because I&amp;rsquo;m going alone but nonetheless it was an amazing experience.
I met a couple of interesting people and mostly I think it boost more my confidence in travelling.
The first day was all about learning Go for Intermediate developers by William Kennedy.
I learned quite a lot, although I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Go in work for some time now, I admit that I still have a long way to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Impression</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/golang-impression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 20:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/golang-impression/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been very excited to use Go at work and somehow very refreshing, been meaning to learn it for some time but it&amp;rsquo;s more easier for me to learn if I actually see it in action.
So far it&amp;rsquo;s been very nice, though of course some stuff are not so easy. Here&amp;rsquo;s one trivial matter.
 First using it with Python feel like I&amp;rsquo;m lost when context switching. Our main application is written in Python/Django and we are slowly trying to build microservices around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS RDS Postgres - ERROR:  must be member of role</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/aws-rds-postgres-error-must-be-member-of-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 01:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/aws-rds-postgres-error-must-be-member-of-role/</guid>
      <description>I recently had to add a user for postgres in AWS RDS but it&amp;rsquo;s giving me this error:
ERROR: must be member of role &amp;quot;test&amp;quot;  So here&amp;rsquo;s what I did:
First create a user with CREATEDB capability:
CREATE USER testuser WITH CREATEDB PASSWORD &#39;testpassword&#39;; \q  Connect again with this new user and create the database:
CREATE DATABASE testdb OWNER testuser;  That&amp;rsquo;s it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recently upgraded Windows on my dual boot laptop causes problems on my bootloader.</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/recently-upgraded-windows-on-my-dual-boot-laptop-causes-problems-on-my-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 04:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/recently-upgraded-windows-on-my-dual-boot-laptop-causes-problems-on-my-linux/</guid>
      <description>So I upgraded my Windows software to the latest insider preview and it kind of messed up my laptop.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the error message:
EFI stub: ERROR: failed to read file. Trying to load files to higher address EFI stub: ERROR: failed to read file.  Here&amp;rsquo;s the step I did to resolved it.
 Boot in an ArchLinux liveusb. Mount your root and boot partition. Chroot into it. And reinstall the bootloader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing python packages directly from Github using pip.</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/installing-python-packages-directly-from-github-using-pip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 03:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/installing-python-packages-directly-from-github-using-pip/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I needed to install a package directly from Github which I&amp;rsquo;m trying to contribute into.
For example you have this url: https://github.com/zkanda/lambda-uploader
What you can do is just add git+ as prefix in the URL.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how you can do it!
pip install git+https://github.com/zkanda/lambda-uploader  But the code that I want to install is from another branch, so how do we do it? We just add @branch_name at the end of the url.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting a different vimrc and runtime for Vim</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/setting-a-different-vimrc-and-runtime-for-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/setting-a-different-vimrc-and-runtime-for-vim/</guid>
      <description>Today, I decided to update my script and search for a way to easily change how I can load vimrc and .vim/ directory. And vim provides a very convenient way to do it using environment variable.
 VIMINIT - for switching vimrc. VIMRUNTIME - for the .vim directory.  You can use it like this:
VIMINIT=/path/to/custom/vimrc vim
and
VIMRUNTIME=/path/to/.vim vim
You can combine them both as well.
Click here for the relevant docs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Selenium Testing Environment</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/a-better-selenium-testing-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 03:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/a-better-selenium-testing-environment/</guid>
      <description>Have you gotten tired of Selenium breaking on every update on your Firefox? Certainly I have. For this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how to use Selenium with their official image in docker hub.
Pros:  Pin a browser to specific version. Same testing environment on all operating system. No more holding upgrade for your browser. Easy scaling.  Cons:  Adds another stack of your learning(which can be a good thing depending on the person)  There are also other paid solutions available which are easier to use but comes with price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting vi mode on IPython 5</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/setting-vi-mode-on-ipython-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 20:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/setting-vi-mode-on-ipython-5/</guid>
      <description>I just upgraded my IPython version to 5 and one thing that I&amp;rsquo;m missing is my vi mode binding. When I read the changelog, they now replace readline with prompt_toolkit a pure python interactive command line prompt. This is very nice because it supports all platform that python supports.
So to bring back your vi binding, you need to do this.
ipython profile create  This will create a default profile where you can change your IPython configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling the latest beta kernel in ArchLinux</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/compiling-the-latest-beta-kernel-in-archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/compiling-the-latest-beta-kernel-in-archlinux/</guid>
      <description>You have a new laptop, you install ArchLinux on it and seems like a some things is missing. Certainly this is the case for me, one of this is suspend feature, when doing, my laptop just seems to boot as if I shutdown it, my application is not persisted. Another is a fix for my headphone noise issue, just to name a few.
 Some things is missing!
 One of the few things you can try is to install the latest beta kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Start of Our Journey....</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/the-start-of-our-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 09:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/the-start-of-our-journey/</guid>
      <description>##Bonjour ! &amp;gt;Everything is a mysterious journey, each with its unique flavor and texture. Here will be the diary, the voice on in which have the influence of something we yet fully understand.
The Realm of Space!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>