<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on The Realm of Space</title>
    <link>https://zkanda.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on The Realm of Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 21:55:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zkanda.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our experience in resizing an EBS volume in EC2 instances.</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/resize-ebs-volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 21:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/resize-ebs-volume/</guid>
      <description>Increasing disk space without downtime.
So in our team, we had to resize an instance disk because it&amp;rsquo;s getting full, this is our experience.
For the first time we search on how to do this, there&amp;rsquo;s many article written about it and most of them requires to stop the system and detaching a volume. But there must be a real docs from aws itself, that is most likely up to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Elasticsearch on a 2GB Digital Ocean Droplet</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/running-elasticsearch-on-a-2gb-digital-ocean-droplet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 04:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/running-elasticsearch-on-a-2gb-digital-ocean-droplet/</guid>
      <description>So I want to run Elasticsearch on a very limited memory machine and I keep running on this error: cannot allocate memory.
Did some research and found this docs on increasing max_map_count:
echo &amp;quot;vm.max_map_count=262144&amp;quot; | sudo tee -a /etc/sysctl.conf sudo sysctl -w vm.max_map_count=262144  But the problem still persist, turns out memory still actually still not enough. I want don&amp;rsquo;t to upgrade the memory since I just want to test things out and I have no plan on running it on production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling the latest beta kernel in ArchLinux</title>
      <link>https://zkanda.github.io/code/compiling-the-latest-beta-kernel-in-archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkanda.github.io/code/compiling-the-latest-beta-kernel-in-archlinux/</guid>
      <description>You have a new laptop, you install ArchLinux on it and seems like a some things is missing. Certainly this is the case for me, one of this is suspend feature, when doing, my laptop just seems to boot as if I shutdown it, my application is not persisted. Another is a fix for my headphone noise issue, just to name a few.
 Some things is missing!
 One of the few things you can try is to install the latest beta kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>